vandykes.com 2008-09-17

# Privacy Policy from Van Dykes

We offer fast and secure online ordering. If you are a new customer to our website, to place an order please set up an account. If you are a previous customer please login to place an order. For easy navigation use the search box at the top of every page or browse through the categories. If you are having problems locating products on our website please call us at 1-800-787-3355. You can order directly by calling 1-800-558-1234.

Great deals for email subscribers, special offers, new products,   
and how-to newsletters. [Sign up today!](http://www.vandykes.com/email.php)

|   
---  
  
  **Free catalog** [Click here](http://www.vandykes.com/catalog.php)   
| 

**Updated 1-14-05 – Important Policy Changes that apply to all Van Dyke’s Customers**

**_What personally identifiable information is being collected?_**

When you visit the Van Dyke’s Web site, in order for us to provide you with the products or services that you have requested, you may be asked to provide us with personally identifiable information. For example, when you order a product, we will ask you to become a registered user of our site, during which you will be asked for your shipping and billing addresses, your email address, and your credit card number or other payment-related information. If you request one of our newsletters or send an inquiry to one of our customer service representatives, we will also store a record of your request along with your email address. In addition, our Web servers track various technical details about your visit, such as you computer’s IP address and which pages you visited, however that information does not typically contain any personally identifiable information about you.

**_How is the information being used?_**

The information we collect is used to provide the products and services that you have requested or that we think you might have an interest in. It is also used to improve the content of our Web site, to notify you of problems with your requests, or to update you about changes to our Web site.

**_With whom do we share your information?_**

In order to operate this Web site and in order to provide you with the products and services you have requested, we need to share information with third parties. We may transmit your personal information to service providers who assist us in processing orders, shipping products to you, processing your payment information, sending you catalogs, conducting surveys, on and offline sweepstakes , sending you emails and newsletters. We have agreements with these service providers that they will protect your privacy in accordance with our standard Privacy Statement. Some of those organizations may have their own Privacy Statements which may give you additional protections, so you are encouraged to read those statements when presented to you.

**_How do I access, update, or delete my personally identifiable information?_**

If you are a registered user of the Web site, you can manage many aspects of your registration information. For security reasons, however, some parts of your personal information may not be changed online and may require you to call or write to us in order to verify your identity before such changes can be made. The online registration area will also permit you to exercise control over the use of your email address, allowing you to opt-out of future email messages from this Web site. Unfortunately, due to various legal and recordkeeping requirements, we may be required to maintain records about your purchases or other activities on this website. However, you will always be permitted to opt-out of any marketing uses of information stored about you. If you prefer to manage your personal information via other means, you may contact us by postal mail at: 

Van Dyke’s  
P.O. Box 278  
Woonsocket, SD 57385-0278

Or by [e-mailing us](mailto:restorers@cabelas.com). 

**_What information will be disclosed if required by law?_**

If required by law, we may provide any and all information we have about you to law enforcement or other government agencies, pursuant to a subpoena, warrant, or other order by a court of competent jurisdiction. In all cases, we will require written documentation of the request, proof of the identity of the law enforcement official making the request, and we will take steps to authenticate the validity of the request. Any law enforcement or government agency request submitted with less than a court-issued order will be evaluated on a case-by-case basis according to the need and urgency, as well as the particular law enforcement agency making the request.

**_What personal information is collected in_** ** _Van Dyke’s Forums and Chat?_**

On certain portions of our Web site, we provide message board and chat features. Those features may require you to provide additional registration information, providing an email address or other information. It is important to understand that when you participate in online discussions, any information you choose to provide is considered “public knowledge” and it is your responsibility to protect your own privacy. You have the choice of making certain information about yourself available to other users of the system. It is your responsibility to manage your account settings in order to maintain the level of privacy that you desire. If you inadvertently post private or other inappropriate information, we will do our best to assist you in removing it, but we will not be responsible for any problems arising from your errors. The message boards and chat features are provided without any warranty and you use them at your own risk.

**_What are cookies and how do we use them?_**

A cookie is a block of text placed in a file on the user's hard drive by a Web site you've visited. These types of cookies cannot identify an individual user specifically, such as by name or address, unless the cookie data is attached to personally identifiable information such as online registration. Van Dyke’s uses cookies to observe our site visitor's navigation throughout the site. This helps us identify ways to improve the shopping experience.

Van Dyke’s also uses a session cookie, which is a piece of identification between your browser and our server, which helps to do things like keep track of the items in a user's shopping cart, and other information. The shopping cart cookie is saved for a designated period of time in case the users’ session expires or they return to complete a purchase in that time frame _._

**_What choices are available to you regarding the collection, use and distribution of the information and how you can correct any inaccuracies in information?_**

If you do not want to receive email from us in the future, please let us know by calling, sending an email, or by writing to us at the above postal address and telling us that you do not want to receive e-mail from our company.

If you provide us with your email address, you may receive messages about your order status, issues regarding the operations of this Web site, and messages from subsidiaries of Van Dyke’s and other companies with operational relationships to Van Dyke’s. You may modify your email preferences at any time by **[www.vandykes.com/login.php](http://www.vandykes.com/login.php). **

If you provide us with your postal address, you may receive periodic catalogs from us, or other notices containing information about new products and services or upcoming events. On occasion, we may make our email and postal mailing address lists available to subsidiaries and affiliated companies that are part of the Van Dyke’s family of companies. We may also make our postal mailing address lists available to other companies who we believe may have products and services of interest to our customers. However, we do not share email addresses with any outside organizations for marketing purposes. If you do not wish to receive postal mailings from Van Dyke’s, its subsidiaries, or third-party organizations, please let us know by calling, sending an email, or writing to us at the above postal address. Please provide us with your exact name and postal address and state which lists you wish to be removed from so that we can be sure your information is removed from those mailing lists.

We will request your telephone number or facsimile (FAX) number, and if you provide it, you may receive telephone or FAX contact from us with information regarding your orders or requests for information. We do not share phone or FAX numbers with third parties for marketing purposes. 

Cabela's Incorporated is the parent company of Van Dyke's Inc.

_Security_

**_What kind of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under our control?_**

Van Dyke’s values your business and is committed to doing everything possible to make our online ordering process secure.

**_Secure Ordering Process_**

Any credit card information you enter on our site is strongly encrypted by industry-standard protocol, SSL (Secure Sockets Layer). The Van Dyke’s Web site uses SSL to communicate with secure browsers like Netscape and Internet Explorer. These browsers encrypt your credit card and personal information in a way that makes it extremely difficult for anyone to intercept and misuse while being transmitted between your computer and our server. Don't worry if your browser is secure or not - if it is insecure, you will not be able to purchase on our online store.

Once you have completed your order online, our security procedures do not end. We take appropriate precautions to protect the security and privacy of the information stored on our computer networks. Many of the systems which store your personal information are not connected to the Internet, reducing the likelihood of security breaches. Our systems are also housed in secure facilities, and access to your data by our employees is limited to a “need to know” basis, controlled by password protected systems, and monitored for abuse. 

If you are still unsure of giving your credit card over the Internet, please feel free to phone, fax, or mail your order to us. For telephone ordering or assistance, please call Van Dyke’s at 1-800-787-3355. Our fax number for Customer Service is 1-605-796-4085 (for US/Canada 1-605-796-4425). Or, send your order to:

Van Dyke’s  
P.O. Box 278  
Woonsocket, SD 57385-0278 

If you have any further question regarding your online security, please contact us at 1-800-787-3355 or [e-mail Customer Service](mailto:restorers@cabelas.com).

**Children**

In accordance with federal law, we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under age 13 without the verifiable permission of a parent or guardian. If you are under age 13, you are welcome to browse our Web site. However you are not permitted to use any of the features of our site that require the collection of any personally identifiable information. If we determine that we have erroneously collected a child’s information, we will immediately undertake to delete that data from our records.

|  |
